=Remnants of Gold=
(Adapted from Gu Long's
"Flying Eagle over the Great Land")
(The main characters
in this drama are fictional)
=Episode 4=
(Heisong Post)
Two goats
are climbing the mountain.
A lady is beckoning.
Should I go over?
The door is locked.
If I don't go,
my heart itches.
Should I go over?
The door is locked.
If I don't go,
my heart itches.
Lead them away.
Water is splashing.
A lady
is taking a bath.
Should I go over?
The door is locked.
If I don't go,
my heart itches.
Bancha, you're back.
You silly fool. Careful.
Be careful with these
two camel-loads of treasures.
Where's the part for the post?
How could I forget your share?
Come on.
Here.
The finest one.
I don't need to give you extra
next time I pass through.
What is this?
How is this any different
from what's on your camel's back?
I do not lie.
What's mine is yours.
It's the finest salt from Gesa Sea.
And what are those two?
The finest liquor from Xining Town.
What?
Nothing.
The finest liquor from Xining?
Let me have a taste.
Taste what?
Even 300,000 taels of gold couldn't
buy this camel-load of liquor.
Who is the post master?
Go.
How nice.
Where is the post master?
I am.
You can call him Zhang.
Come over here.
From now on,
people may enter the Post,
but no one leaves.
Imperial court business.
What?
What is going on?
Embroidered Uniform Guard.
The Imperial Court.
Liangzhou Guard.
This is Officer Pu
of the Embroidered Uniform Guard.
On official business.
All right.
Entry allowed, and no leaving?
Can I go back to Wusu Sea
tomorrow morning?
Who are you?
Bancha.
Tea fetcher?
It's Bancha.
It's my name.
Bancha who does not lie.
Yes.
I do not lie.
That's hard for ordinary people to do.
So you are no ordinary man.
I am just an ordinary man
who can manage not to lie.
Lead all the horses out.
If I had known this...
Leave ten men here.
Ten men inside.
Let me taste it.
Set the ambush.
Await my command.
Ambush. Follow Officer Pu's orders.
Tie up all the horses.
What mess is this?
Officer Pu,
what about me?
Why did you come in here?
You're just a coroner.
Is that for me?
I was afraid you'd think I smell bad.
It smells awful?
Don't come over.
Stay away from me.
The whole desert smells like this.
Isn't it great?
You people just don't get it.
Let's go.
Isn't it great?
The sun is fragrant.
The yellow sand is fragrant.
The desert is full of
the scent of sun and yellow sand.
As long as you roll around in the sand,
you carry the scent of
the sun and yellow sand,
the true smell of the great desert.
(Arriving at Heisong Post)
Nine is almost at Heisong Post.
We'll spend the night here
and leave tomorrow.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Yes, sir.
No meat?
No.
You dummy,
I...
I gave you a large bag
of the finest salt from Gesa Sea.
You call this a large bag?
Do you want it or not?
Is it the finest, or isn't it?
It is the finest.
What is this stuff?
So bland.
Winter rain is more
intoxicating than this.
If your liquor is so good,
why don't you bring it out
for us to drink?
Keep your voice down.
What?
Nothing.
Officer Pu.
Officer,
over here.
Over here.
Upstairs on the second floor,
it's just an old couple.
Bring them down.
The old woman seems to be sick,
lying in bed.
You.
Get down here.
Officer Pu.
Very fine highland barley liquor.
Lady,
you know liquor?
I can't speak loudly,
so you shout it.
Shout what?
Tell those two men not to move.
Guards, attack. Take them down.
Don't move!
It's you two!
Men, seize them!
Very fine highland barley.
It was distilled four times,
likely made with
water from Haima Spring.
It is indeed snowmelt from
Tianshan at Haima Spring.
Connecting heaven and earth,
sweet, crisp, and refreshing.
Nobody move.
Just this water alone
invigorates the tendons and bones.
May I have a bowl?
I'll pay in gold.
I'll go get another liquor bowl.
Wait here.
Move forward.
Step forward.
Forward.
(Heisong Post)
Put down all your weapons.
Whoever doesn't put them down
is the spy who placed the escort order
and slaughtered 27 members
of the Zhang family.
Get me a liquor bowl.
Luyao,
Pingping,
should we listen to him?
Officer Pu is a Seventh Rank
official of the imperial court.
Of course we must listen to him.
This won't do. Switch to another one.
Fine, then.
Still running? You're
still running? Still running?
You, tea fetcher.
He's going to fetch liquor for me.
Go fetch it.
You.
Put down your weapon.
Name.
Surname Fang.
Just call me Fang.
And you?
Lamp Shade.
Nobody is named Lamp Shade.
Well, my name is Lamp Shade.
Miss Zhang's
recruitment was just posted.
How did you happen to be in Liangzhou?
I was traveling with a merchant caravan,
fell ill, and stayed in
Liangzhou for half a month.
What kind of caravan?
Silk and tea leaves,
126 camels,
and headed east from
Liangzhou half a month ago.
Answering everything you're asked...
Did you memorize this in advance?
Officer Pu, you live up
to your name and title.
He did memorize it in advance.
Ask him if he wants to know
how Seven and Sixteen died.
Do you want to know?
In our eyes,
you are nothing.
What do you mean?
I was supposed to
at least reach Lieyang Well.
You're not going anywhere.
Seize him.
Whose man are you?
Every single one of you will die.
Seize him!
Block him. Officer!
Hold on a moment.
Officer, wait a second.
Wait a second.
Fang, don't move.
Officer...
Come on, lady.
Have a taste.
Officer.
Protect the Officer.
How?
Is the liquor good?
You're no ordinary person.
I'm just Bancha, the one who never lies.
They all know it.
Yes. He's just an ordinary man
who doesn't lie.
That's right.
Good liquor is worth
a grain of gold per sip.
Protect the Officer.
Drink up.
Do you know what this is?
What?
Hurry, Officer.
Officer, run.
Hurry, run.
Protect the Officer.
Officer.
An unpalatable bean.
It's a type of poison.
I give you good liquor,
and you give me
poison?
Protect the Officer...
Don't go over there...
Do I need your protection, huh?
You put it in your own mouth.
Don't worry.
(Do I need your protection?)
It won't poison a human.
Then, what does it poison?
Only beasts will be poisoned.
Why do I feel like you're insulting me?
Fang.
Pingping,
tell Fang to subdue him,
but spare his life.
Fang,
make a move.
Don't go over there again.
Liquor...
Don't move.
If you touch me again, I'll kill you!
I won't move.
Luyao.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Fang,
are you okay?
I'm fine.
Officer.
Luyao told you to spare his life.
Coroner,
check if he's dead or not.
He's dead.
The eagle earlier
flew away before we entered the post
and took 15 minutes to fly back.
They use eagles to pass messages.
Horses are slightly slower than eagles.
The person who placed the escort
order with my father and brothers
is only around 23 minutes away from us.
Search in the direction the eagle flew.
Their planted spy is dead,
so why haven't they left?
Besides, it's getting dark.
What do you mean?
We head to Lieyang Well tomorrow.
Now, eat and drink.
Futu.
What's wrong?
Nine is dead.
Two goats are grazing.
The dead man is lying right here?
It'll be very hot when the sun
comes up tomorrow.
We have a coroner.
He'll find a place
to bury him late at night.
She's beckoning to me.
Should I go over?
The lady is taking a bath.
If I go over,
the door is locked.
If I don't go,
my heart itches.
I'm up on the hillside.
Go call Fang over to eat together.
There's a lady
in the distance.
The lady
is beckoning to me.
Should I go over?
The door is locked.
If I don't go over...
Are the people here not
afraid of government troops?
Luyao asked you to come over and eat.
You should have
brought more soldiers with you.
Under the vast sky,
all land belongs to the King.
How many would be considered enough?
I just don't believe it.
Luyao.
Officer Pu.
Sit.
I'm fine standing.
Sit when you're told to.
The door is locked.
We'll reach Lieyang Well tomorrow.
We'll run into
the guardians of the gold,
and the person who
hired my escort agency
will finally show themselves.
Are you afraid?
I want to go over,
but the door is locked.
She asked if you're afraid.
If I don't go over...
I'm not afraid of them,
just that they might poison us secretly
instead of fighting us openly.
This is the feed poison the guardians
of the gold used on my family.
As long as we're careful,
with me around,
the poison won't harm anyone.
Then I won't be afraid anymore.
Dummy.
Two big jars and two big bundles,
placed right here.
Not a bit less.
I'm going to sleep.
You can sleep in peace.
Sleep.
Bancha, who never lies.
What?
Can we drink
your highland barley liquor?
No.
We'll buy it.
You can't afford it.
We'll buy it with gold.
Not for sale, no matter how much gold.
How about 100 taels of gold?
You must be joking.
Fifty taels for one jar,
and one hundred taels for two.
I do not lie.
If you can bring out 100 taels of gold,
everyone gets to drink these two jars
of highland barley liquor.
Bring out the gold.
(Awe-inspiring in Northern Deserts)
Is General resting?
I want to see General.
By order of General Ha,
unauthorized personnel
shall not disturb General.
Am I unauthorized?
Step aside.
Anyone trespassing
in General's inner courtyard
shall be executed on the spot.
I am the Deputy Military Commissioner
of Liangzhou Guard.
I've been through life and death
with General for 20 years.
My friend,
executed on the spot, huh?
Please wait, Deputy.
I'll go report to General Ha.
How does the dead guy
have so much money?
I gave it to him.
Two hundred taels to hire two killers.
Didn't expect one of them to be a spy.
The other hundred taels is with me.
Are you a spy?
I...
I take people's money,
and I do what I'm paid to do.
Luyao, your life is my life.
I'll do whatever you ask me to do.
Really?
Really.
You're just a young man.
Why do you need so much gold, too?
It's fine if I don't get any.
Don't want it anymore?
I want gold.
Who wouldn't want gold?
Pour me another bowl.
I'm not a kid.
None of you believes me.
If there was no gold,
would you still be
willing to go west with us?
I would.
Why?
You're a good person, Luyao.
And Fang here is a decent,
good person, too.
How do you know I'm a good person?
Your family was framed
with a fake escort order
and then wiped out by
the guardians of the gold.
A real man ought to
help catch the killers
and eradicate evil.
Drink up.
I've already had several bowls.
I'm feeling dizzy.
I believe you.
Drink.
I rarely drink.
I get sleepy as soon as I drink.
Give me some.
Dummy,
such good liquor,
and you just gulp it down like that?
Good liquor.
Let us have a taste.
Another bowl.
Deputy, please wait in the front hall.
General Ha will be right here.
Open the doors.
(May Divine Might Protect Us Forever)
Does Miss Zhang know martial arts?
She is very good at it.
That's why she's so bold.
Watch your step.
Even the roof was broken through.
I'll leave you some money
tomorrow morning for repairs.
No need.
Well,
the Liangzhou guards are here,
and so are
the Embroidered Uniform Guards.
The inn is so run-down.
The government
will repair it later anyway.
An old couple from Yongchang
asked for a pot of water this morning
and never opened their door again.
Do you think this room is alright?
It's great.
Then, please get some rest early.
Congratulations
on earning 100 taels of gold.
Doesn't it feel like a dream?
What dream?
I regret it so much.
Why would I even want gold?
So many men back at Wusu Sea were
waiting for those two jars of liquor.
They've been waiting
for over two months.
How am I supposed to
explain it to them when I go back?
Gold is everywhere.
Every jar of
highland barley liquor brewed
from Haima Spring is one less jar left.
Gold is everywhere?
What does this 100 taels even count for?
I was supposed to be angry.
These past few days,
I don't even know who
I should direct this anger at anymore.
If a man is angry, he should vent it.
If something is bothering you,
spit it out.
The people here don't treat gold
like it's worth anything.
Refusing 200 taels of gold
offered for free...
And 100 taels of gold
are said to be worth less
than two jars of liquor.
They show no respect
to imperial officials,
and they dare to fight
government troops when they see them.
If this were back in the Capital,
it'd feel like a dream.
Who
refused 200 taels of gold
offered for free?
Me.
My friend,
what is your name?
Pu Ying.
Most people can hardly do that.
Offered for free,
with no price attached?
There is a price.
It costs my dignity.
If it costs your dignity,
you don't want the gold?
Would you take it?
Pu Ying,
if you ever come to Wusu Sea one day,
my yurt will be your yurt,
and my men
will be your men.
If you ever go to the Capital one day,
while
I can't give you a house,
buying you food and drinks
won't be a problem at all.
(Preview of the Next Episode)
My name is Tie Futu.
Don't get in the way
of Futu's work.
Down you go.
The one placing the escort order
and the one poisoning...
Both are me.
Capture the Zhang lady.
=Remnants of Gold=